lan Kirkland

iankirkland00@gmail.com

Insightful writer, editor, and market analyst. Seasoned and meticulous management of bespoke marketing campaigns. Expertly skilled in editorial critique and trend projection. Cogent and intuitive writing tailored to and invested in today's most promising global and digital markets.

Education

- University Of Edinburgh English Literature & Linguistics MA Awarded: First Edinburgh, Scotland 2018 - 2022
- UCLA French Language Intensive Grade: 4.0 GPA Remote 06/2020-08/2020
- Northern Virginia Writing Project
 July Institute: Creative Writing
 Fairfax, VA
 07/2017

References

Mindy Thomas
Tinkercast CEO/Host/Producer
mindy@tinkercast.com

<u>Fizzy Meredith</u> Queermunity Founder fizzy.queermunity@gmail.com

Skills

- English, French, German fluency
- Account Management Expertise
- Adobe Creative Suite, Airtable, G-Suite
- Writing Engaging Copy for PRs, Websites,
 Newsletters, Social Media, Speeches, Video.

Experience

Podcast Production Consultant

Tinkercast—Washington, DC—07/2022

- One of four writers selected to develop and produce the forthcoming second season of the podcast.
- Conceived of the show's structure, characters, story arcs, themes, and marketing strategies.
- Pitched show to production company Gen-Z Media.
- SDI Ediplometry Library Volunteer
 - SPL—Edinburgh—06/2021 08/2022
 - Implemented new cataloguing/archiving system.
 - Wrote for & edited author bios for the SPL website.
 - Assisted in the management of library events including publication tours, readings, and open mic nights.
- * Theatre Weekly Critic

Theatre Weekly-Edinburgh-06/2019 - 08/2022

- Reviewed shows at the Edinburgh Fringe Festivals https://theatreweekly.com/author/ian-kirkland/

Events Organiser

PublishED—Edinburgh—04/2019 - 06/2020

- Planned literary workshops, panels with authors, publishers, & agents, and open mic nights.
- Published monthly newsletters featuring new articles, event lineups, news commentary, interactive polls, freelance opportunities, and more.
- Worked with SYP (Society of Young Publishers).

Publishing Intern

Touchpoint Press-Remote-10/2019 - 11/2019

- Contacted authors/bookshops, drafted book blurbs/ Press Releases, updated media logs & social media (Website, PRLOG, Meta, Hootsuite, PM).

Events Strategist

FX Players—Fairfax, VA—10/2016 - 05/2018

- Spearheaded community fundraising efforts by organising biannual theatre camps of up to 200 children aged 6-14 and raised roughly 10,000 USD per camp.
- Mobilised camp committee, trained teachers/ counsellors, scheduled workshops, allocated budget.